COLIN BIRDWELL

CONTACT

Address: Tomball Texas 77375

Phone: (713) 542-4597

Email: web.by.birdwell@gmail.com

http://www.webbybirdwell.com/

https://github.com/C-Birdwell

SKILLS

• HTML: Expert

· CSS: Expert

· Javascript: Expert

• React: Intermediate

· React-Native: Advanced

· Redux: Intermediate

• Axios: Intermediate

· Jquery: Advanced

ModX: Expert

· Node.js: Intermediate

· Version Control: Advanced

· UI/UX: Advanced

· Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator: Beginner

Npm: Intermediate

Gulp: Intermediate

• ECommerce: Intermediate

Hubspot: Advanced

· Big Commerce: Advanced

• Bootstrap: Expert

Flexbox: Intermediate

• CSS Grid: Intermediate

• Formstack: Advanced

 Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, etc., Custom Email Template creation: Advanced

• Bitbucket: Advanced

Github: Advanced

• Yarn: Intermediate

• Visual Studio: Intermediate

• Git: Intermediate

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Determined Web Developer offering more than five years of experience. Colin has worked with online and digital businesses both as a web & app developer, in the industries of private agencies, online commerce, local government, utilities, and the financial banking. Bringing more than five years of experience, Colin can handle your front end coding needs. As an App Developer, he built the front end of a personal banking debit card app while using a in house api to update the backend. Colin incorporated concepts of templating components, extensive visual animations, and haptic feedback. As a Web Developer, his skills include working knowledge of several various web based languages, User Experience & User Interface design (UX/UI), online interactions, web design, and working within small, innovative teams of developers in an Agile/Scrum setting. Colin also has extensive knowledge on IT operations, middleware experience, and some full-stack experience with things like Node.js, Postgres, GrapshQL, Prisma, and MongoDB. Self-motivated Web Developer with high level of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in role with company promoting best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

WORK HISTORY

Web Developer, 01/2014 to Current **Freelance Web Developer** - Houston, TX

As a freelance web developer, I help smaller clients with a variety of web-related needs:

- Created and maintained websites
- General consultation for project development
- Social media and SEO tools into development integration
- Creating full-stack applications consisting of React/ GraphQL /Postgres

Front End Developer, 04/2018 to 07/2019 **Payment Data Systems Inc.** - San Antonio, TX

Was main lead front end developer on rebuilding their proprietary financial debit card banking app white label template Akimbo onto a react-native platform. App requirements included:

- · Heavy React-Native development
- · Animating visual components with haptic feedback
- Card/Bank to card transfers
- Scheduling recurring transfers (utilizing Moment.js to calculate future dates to pick from)
- Using keychain to store secure login information & touch id biometrics
- Utilizing environmental files for on boarding clients to utilize their branding for templating purposes
- Assisting and monitored digital art assets for maintaining consistent brand guidelines

Sass: Advanced

• GraphQL: Beginner

• MongoDB: Beginner

• Design patterns and principles

UI improvements

Web Developer Consultant, 01/2017 to 02/2018 **San Antonio Water System Via Sistema Technologies** - San Antonio, Texas

The main project worked was a customer portal that handled water bill account needs.

- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices
- Coordinating responsive web development with project leads
- Advised on UX/UI related matters
- Integrated web technologies with legacy systems

Web Developer, 09/2014 to 06/2016 **Signet Interactive** - Houston, TX

- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen client's brand and identity.
- Developed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Firefox, Chrome and Safari.
- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts: 2009 **University of Houston** - Houston